<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Welcome to my website on Testing</title>
    <link>/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Welcome to my website on Testing</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A Future Talk</title>
      <link>/blog/a-future-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/a-future-talk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Story&amp;rsquo;s talks pages can highlight upcoming appearances, promoting your talks
before you present. This is a dummy page illustrating this capability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll have to add &lt;code&gt;buildFuture: true&lt;/code&gt; to your site&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code&gt;config.yaml&lt;/code&gt; to enable
this setting.  Talks pages that are in the future won&amp;rsquo;t appear on the homepage
or in your RSS feeds; they&amp;rsquo;ll only appear in the &lt;code&gt;/talks/&lt;/code&gt; list page of your
site.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Story&#39;s Image Formatting Controls</title>
      <link>/images/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/images/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This article is a demo of Story&amp;rsquo;s image-related features (other than &lt;a href=&#34;/figures&#34;&gt;figure captions&lt;/a&gt;).
Story can apply a variety of stylistic and layout transformations to your images.
These features are enabled by unobtrusive, accessibility-friendly tricks that give you more control over images than Markdown typically provides.
Story also has out-of-the-box support for header and preview images, for a visually stunning site.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating Beautiful Presentations with Story</title>
      <link>/blog/adirondack/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 16:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/adirondack/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a &amp;ldquo;talk&amp;rdquo; page in Story, which is the permanent homepage for a talk
you&amp;rsquo;ve given at a specific event. It&amp;rsquo;s designed to showcase your appearance by
bringing together information about the event, along with your slides and extra
information like a video of your talk. In this way you can build a portfolio of
your speaking history.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating Beautiful Presentations with Story</title>
      <link>/slides/adirondack/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2018 09:50:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/slides/adirondack/</guid>
      <description>class: title, smokescreen, shelf, no-footer background-image: url(leo-serrat-533922-unsplash.jpg)
Creating Beautiful Presentations With Remark, Apron, Adirondack, and Descartes The Story Remark Themes Story offers helper themes for creating beautiful presentations with Remark, using simple Markdown to create slide layouts.
 Apron defines the layouts&amp;rsquo; structure and size. Adirondack adds typography, theme colors, and helpful features. Descartes provides element and image positioning and colors.  Story has a design goal of clean, simple Markdown content.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>